-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
僅供交流 嚴禁商用
字幕來源：ljy2006ljy2006@shooter.com
字幕調校：EvineDeng
沃特·迪斯尼（Walt Disney）公司出品
星銀島  Treasure  Planet
旁白：在一個晴空萬里的夜晚
NARRATOR: On the clearest of nights...
伊塞林上和風徐徐
when the winds of the Etherium were calm and peaceful...
滿載大角星水晶的商船
the great merchant ships...with their cargoes of Arcturian sura crystals...
讓人感覺那麼安全
felt safe and secure.
誰也沒想到， 他們早就被人盯上了
Little did they suspect that they were pursued by...
那就是海盜！
pirates.
這些海盜中最可怕就是
And the most feared of all these pirates...
聲名狼藉的船長： 納撒尼爾·弗林特
was the notorious Captain Nathaniel Flint.
開炮！
Fire!
啊！
Aah!
像只折翼的小鷹 承受著突如其來掠奪
Like a Candarian zap-wing overtaking its prey--
詹姆斯·普萊迪斯·霍金斯
James Pleiades Hawkins.
一小時前你就該去上床睡覺了.
I thought you were asleep an hour ago.
媽媽，我剛看到最精彩的部分
Mom, I was just getting to the best part.
求您了！
Please?
哦，精神百倍啊？
Oh, can those eyes get any bigger?
過去點
Scootch over.
旁白：像只折翼的小鷹
...Iike a Candarian zap-wing...
承受著突如其來掠奪
overtaking its prey...
弗林特和他的叛軍
Flint and his band of renegades...
猛衝進去
swooped in out of nowhere.
哈 哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha ha!
掠奪他們的戰利品
And then. gathering up their spoils...
然後，消失得無影無蹤
vanished without a trace.
-霍！ -霍！
-Ooh! -Ooh!
旁白：沒人發現弗林特的秘密寶藏
Flint's secret trove was never found...
所有的傳說都說那些寶藏仍藏在
but stories have persisted that it remains hidden...
銀河中一個遙遠的地方
somewhere at the farthest reaches of the galaxy...
藏匿著
stowed with riches beyond imagination--
自上千個星球掠奪來的巨大財富
the loot of a thousand worlds...
星銀島 星銀島
Treasure Planet.
好了，擤一下鼻涕
OK. Blow your nose.
媽媽，你覺得弗林特船長是怎麼做到的？
How do you think Captain Flint did it, Mom?
他怎麼衝下去後， 就消失得無影無蹤呢？
How'd he swoop in out of nowhere and vanished without a trace?
我不知道
I have no idea.
過來，快快快
Come here, you, you li--
我要吹了！哦！
I'm gonna get--oh!
好了，該睡覺了
OK, now it's time for this
你覺得會有人找到星銀島嗎？
You think somebody'll ever find Treasure Planet?
寶貝，我想
Sweetheart,
那只是一個傳說
Iike a legend.
我知道那是真的
I know it's real.
好好，你說得對，那是真的
You win. It's real.
-晚安，媽媽！ -晚安，寶貝！
-Nighty-night, Mom. -Nighty-night, sweetheart.
我愛你！
I love you.
我也愛你！
Love you, too.
旁白：夜晚，伊塞林的風
There are nights when the winds of the Etherium...
自由自在的飛舞著
so inviting in their promise of flight and freedom...
令每個人情緒激昂！
made one's spirit soar!
十二年後
呀－呼！
Yaaaa-hoo!
嗚呼——！
Whoo!
加速！
Come on!
嗚呼——！哈哈哈哈！
Whoo! Ha ha ha!
嗚呼——！
Whoo-hoo!
哦！我的天！
Oh, great.
（旅館）
霍金斯夫人！
Mrs. Hawkins!
來了－ 把果汁裝滿
I know-- refill on the purp juice.
馬上就來！敦萊蒂夫人！
Coming right up, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
上菜了，四份玻璃球粉
There we go. That's four powdered spheroids...
兩份月蝕。 還有一大碗
two lunar eclipses, and it's a big bowl...
澤勒林果凍蟲，給這個大男孩的！
of Zorellian jelly worms for the big boy!
-太好了！ -慢用！
-Awesome! -Enjoy.
對不起，德爾波特！ 今天早上這裏鬧哄哄的.
Sorry, Delbert. It's been a madhouse here all morning.
沒事，莎拉！
No problem, Sarah.
啊，我的加種子的阿爾伯尼雜燴
Ah! My Alponian chowder with the extra solara seed.
呣——！
Mmm! Yum!
你好啊！
Hello.
你從哪來？
What brings you here...
好奇的小傢伙？
curious little...one?
走吧！
Go away.
你爸媽呢？
Are your parents around?
怎麼了？ 啞巴了？呀——！
What's the matter? Cat got your--yaah!
歐，這年紀的孩子真可愛！
Oh, they're so adorable at that age.
歐，是的！真可惜
Oh, yes...deplorable.
哦，是可愛！呣！
Uh...adorable! Hmm.
說起這個 吉姆怎麼樣了？
Speaking of which, how's Jim doing?
好多了。我知道年初
Much better. I know he had some rough spots...
他受到打擊。 但我想
earlier this year, but I really think...
他會度過難關的！
that he's starting to turn a corner.
霍金斯夫人？
Mrs. Hawkins?
吉姆！
Jim!
哦，看來還沒完
Ooh...wrong turn.
好了，謝謝你們送我回來！
OK. Thanks for the lift, guys.
別急！
Not so fast.
我們發現您的兒子
We apprehended your son operating...
在禁區裏駕駛太陽能車
a solar vehicle in a restricted area.
違反了904條例中
Moving violation 9-0-4...
第15節
section fifteen,
第6？
Six?
-謝謝！ -不客氣！
-Thank you. -Don't mention it.
-吉姆！ --您知道的
-Jim! -As you are aware, ma'am...
這是違反條例的
this constitutes a violation of his probation.
是的，是的！不！我明白。 呣，我們是不是可以....
Yes, yes. No, I understand. Um, but could we just--
嗯，打擾一下
Um. ahem. pardon me.
長官，我是不是可以說一句？
Officers, if I might, uh, interject here.
我是著名的物理學家， 德爾波特·多普勒博士
I am the noted astrophysicist Dr. Delbert Doppler.
你們應該聽說過我
Perhaps you've heard of me.
不知道？嗯，我這裏有個剪報！
No? Uh, I have a clipping.
-您是男孩的父親？ -哦！我的天，不是！
-Are you the boy's father? -Oh! Good heavens, no!
哦！他是我們家的好朋友！
Eww! He's just an old friend of the family.
退回去，先生！
Back off, sir!
謝謝！德爾波特。 我會解決的！
Thank you, Delbert. I will take it from here.
好的，莎拉，如果你堅持這樣...
Well, Sarah, if you insist.
啊咳，以後別讓我這麼做了
Ahem. Don't ever let me do that again.
由於他再三違反15C條例
Due to repeated violations of statute 1 5-C...
我們扣押了他的車子， 如果再犯
we have impounded his vehicle. Any more slip-ups will result...
我們定會將他送進少管所！
in a one-way ticket to Juvenile Hall.
-少兒監獄 -監獄
-Kiddie hoosegow. -The slammo.
謝謝長官！ 以後不會再發生了！
Thank you, officers. It won't happen again.
我們會時刻監視著他
We see his type all the time, ma'am.
-錯誤的選擇. -終結者！
-Wrong choices. -Dead-enders.
失敗者！
Losers.
-好自為之！ -我們走！
-You take care now. -Let's motor.
吉姆，我早就跟你說過了！
Jim, I have had it.
你真的想去少管所？ 是不是？
Do you want to go to Juvenile Hall? Is that it?
吉姆？
Jim?
吉姆，看著我！
Jim, look at me.
我辛辛苦苦維持這個旅館
It's been hard enough keeping this place...
全是我一個人忙呼， 你做過什麼？
afloat by myself without you going--
媽媽，別大驚小怪的！ 一直都是你一個人！
Mom, it's no big deal. There was nobody around.
那些警察只是把我的車子拿走了
Those cops just won't get off my--
算了吧
Forget it.
霍金斯夫人！我的果汁！
Mrs. Hawkins! My juice!
知道，我馬上來！ 敦萊蒂夫人！
Yes, I'll be right there, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
吉姆，我只是不想看到你...
Jim, I just don't want to see you...
放棄自己的將來
throw away your entire future.
將來, 什麼將來？
Yeah, what future?
難以想像你是怎麼維持下來的，莎拉
I really don't know how you manage it. Sarah.
要經營生意， 還要帶大一個像
Trying to run a business while raising a felon like--
像吉姆這樣的孩子
felon...fellow... fellow like Jim.
維持？ 我已經沒辦法了
Managing it? I'm at the end of my rope.
對他父親的離開
Ever since his father left...
吉姆一直都耿耿於懷
well. Jim's just never recovered.
你知道他有多聰明的
And you know how smart he is.
他八歲的時候 做了第一個太陽能滑板
He built his first solar surfer when he was eight!
之後，他就沒上過學
And yet. he's failing at school...
他不斷地惹麻煩
he is constantly in trouble...
跟他說話的時候， 他就像個陌生人
and when I talk to him. he's like a stranger to me.
我不知道為什麼。德爾波特， 我已經盡力了！
I don't know. Delbert. I've tried everything--
嗨，先生！
Hey, Mister?
罐子裏的先生，你還好嗎？
Mister,
啊——！
Aah!
他馬上來了
He's a-comin'.
你聽到他說話了嗎？
Can you hear him?
那些齒輪和陀螺呼呼的轉著
Those gears and gyros clickin' and whirrin'...
就像那個惡魔一樣！
Iike the devil himself!
哦，撞暈頭了？
Uh, hit your head there pretty hard, didn't ya?
他來搶我的箱子
He's after me chest...
那個殘忍的機器人 還有他的屠殺部隊
that fiendish cyborg and his band of cutthroats.
但是他們必須
But they'll have to pry it...
先從比利·鮑恩斯冰冷的 死人的手指中探察
from old Billy Bones' cold, dead fingers afore l--argh!
哦，我的...
Oh, my--
哦，來吧，把胳膊給我
Uh, come on, give me your arm.
對了
That's it.
-好孩子。 -我這麼做媽媽會很高興的
-Good lad. -Mom's gonna love this.
德爾波特，感謝您聽你我嘮叨。
Thanks for listening, Delbert.
我好多了
It helps.
一切都會好的
It's going to be OK.
放心吧
You'll see.
我一直希望， 有一天我打開門...
I keep dreaming one day I'll open that door...
他會像以前一樣
and there he'll be just the way he was.
一個開朗、快樂的男孩， 抱著一隻新寵物...
A smiling, happy little boy, holding a new pet...
讓我允許收留它
and begging me to let him keep it.
詹姆斯·普萊迪斯·霍金斯
James Pleiades Hawkins!
媽媽，他受傷了 傷得很重
Mom, he's hurt...bad!
我的箱子，小伙子
Me chest, lad.
他馬上就來了
He'll be comin' soon.
不能讓他找到這東西
Can't let them find this.
誰要來？
Who's coming?
機器人！
The cyborg!
小心那機器人！
Beware the cyborg!
哦！
Ohh!
快！我們必須馬上離開這兒！
Quick! We gotta go!
-哦！ -啊！
-Ohh! -Aah!
我想這時候我離不開吉姆了！
I believe I'm with Jim on this one!
黛利拉！（原是聖經中人物） 哈利路亞！
Delilah! Hallelujah!
呆在那兒！ 別動！
Stay! Don't move!
那東西呢？
Where is it?!
把它找出來！
Find it!
不用擔心，莎拉！
Don't worry. Sarah.
我是個物理學專家
I'm an expert in the laws of physical science.
-我們數到三。一... -三！
-On the count of three--one... -Three!
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
快，黛利拉，快！
Go, Delilah! Go!
快走！對極了！快！
Go! That's it! That's it! Go!
駕！駕！
Hyah! Hyah!
我跟警察說了
I just spoke with the constabulary.
那些海盜逃走的時候 沒有留下任何線索！
Those blaggard pirates have fled without a trace.
我很難過，莎拉！
I'm sorry, Sarah.
我想老本鮑旅館已經化為灰燼了
I'm afraid the old Benbow lnn has burned to the ground.
對了， 都是那個小球帶來的麻煩！
Ahem. Well, certainly a lot of trouble...over that odd little sphere.
那些標記看起來挺奇怪的
Those markings baffle me.
我從沒見過像這樣的東西
Unlike anything I've ever encountered.
就是以我豐富的經驗
Even with my vast experience...
和驚人的智慧
and superior intellect...
都得花好幾年才能打開它
it would take me years to unlock its--hey!
什麼？是張地圖！
Why, it's a map!
等等！等等！
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
這是我們，在特雷斯普行星
This is us,
那是麥哲倫雲層
That's the Magellanic Cloud!
哦！珊瑚星系！
Whoo! The Coral Galaxy!
哦！
Oh!
那是天鵝星座！
That's the Cygnus Cross...
克裏安黑洞！
and that's the Kerian Abyss.
等等！這是什麼？這是什麼？ 奇怪，它是...
Wait. What's this? What's this? Why, it--it's...
星銀島！
Treasure Planet.
不！
No!
是星銀島！
That's Treasure Planet!
弗林特的寶藏？
Flint's trove?
掠奪上千個世界的戰利品？
The loot of a thousand worlds?
你知道這意味著什麼嗎？
You know what this means?
就是說所有的財寶只是在一艘船上。
It means that all that treasure is only a boat ride away.
有了它就有了全世界
Whoever brings it back would hold an eternal place...
高高的站在萬神殿上受萬人朝拜！ 想必他就是這樣！
atop the pantheon of explorers! He'd be able to experience--
哦！剛才怎麼了？
Whoo! What just happened?
媽媽，就是這個！ 這是所有問題的答案！
Mom, this is it. This is
吉姆，這絕對不可能！
Jim, there is
您還記得那些故事嗎？
Don't you remember, all those stories?
就是了，他們只是故事！
That's all they were--stories!
有了那些財寶
With that treasure...
我們可以建造數百個本鮑旅館
we could rebuild the Benbow a hundred times over!
哦，這是...這到底是...
Well, this is--
德爾波特，你可以解釋這個荒謬的事情？
Delbert, would you please explain how ridiculous this is?
真是太荒謬了
It's totally preposterous...
一個人穿過整個星系
traversing the entire galaxy alone.
好了，現在乖乖呆在這兒吧
Now at last,
-所以我要和你一起去！ -德爾波特！
-That's why I'm going with you. -Delbert!
用我的積蓄來作為探險隊的費用
I'll use my savings to finance the expedition.
我要搞艘船， 雇一個船長還有一個水手隊！
I'll commission a ship, hire a captain and a crew.
你不是認真的吧？
You're not serious.
我這輩子就等這麼個機會了
All my life I've been waiting for an opportunity like this...
我聽到了一個聲音： 「前進吧，德爾波特！前進吧，德爾波特」
and here it is screaming, "Go, Delbert! Go, Delbert!"
好了，好了！ 你們兩個都瘋了！
OK. OK! You're both grounded!
媽媽，你看
Mom. Iook...
我知道我讓這裏亂七八糟的
I know that I keep messing everything up...
我知道
and I know...
我讓你失望
that I let you down.
但這是我向你證明我自己的機會
But this is my chance to make it up to you.
我會把一切處理的妥妥當當的
I'm gonna set things right.
莎拉？
Sarah?
可以嗎？
If I may?
你說你已經沒辦法了
You said yourself, you've tried everything.
沒有比在太空中鍛煉的幾個月
There are much worse remedies...
更好的補救方法了
than a few character-building months in space.
你這麼說是因為 這麼做是對的
Are you saying this because it's the right thing...
還是因為你真的想去？
or because you really want to go?
真的，真的，真的， 真的想去
I really, really, really, really want to go...
而且這麼做是對的！
and it's the right thing.
吉姆
Jim...
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
媽媽，我也捨不得
Mom...you won't.
我不會讓你失望的
I'll make you proud.
好了，哦
Well. uh. ahem.
我們這不是在一起嗎？
There we are then.
我們馬上開始準備
We'll begin preparations at once.
吉姆，我的孩子， 我們馬上要升上太空了
Jim, my boy, soon we'll be off to the spaceport.
吉姆，等等我！
Jim! Oh. Jim! Wait for me!
哦，吉姆，我們
Well, Jim, this should be
應該好好的互相瞭解一下
for the two of us to get to know one another.
你知道他們說什麼， 親情溝通，呣
You know what they say, familiarity breeds, um...
這樣說不太禮貌 但是，在我麼看來...
well, contempt, but, in our case--
走吧，找找我們的船！
Look, let's just find the ship. OK?
-你右手邊的第二個泊位！ -你可以找到的！
-Second berth on your right! -You can't miss it.
嘿，謝謝！
Hey, thanks.
合適嗎？
It's the suit, isn't it?
那個可惡的女店員！
to that pushy two-headed saleswoman.
這個說合適！
This one said it fit,
哦不知道該怎麼辦。 我都有些混亂了！哦！
I didn't know what to do. I get so flustered. Ooh!
歐，吉姆！這是我們的船！ R.L.S.的遺產！
Oh, Jim! This is our ship! The R.L.S. Legacy!
哇！
Whoa!
把這些桶搬上去！
Stow those casks forward!
拉上去！
Heave together now!
太酷了！
How cool is this?
對不起，我是說...
Sorry about that. I didn't mean--
讓我來
Allow me to handle this.
吉姆，我的弗拉圖拉語很流利！
I'm fluent in Flatula, Jim.
我在大學裏學了兩年！
Took two years of it in high school.
弗拉圖拉？太酷了！
Flatula? Cool.
早上好，船長！ 都準備好了嗎？
Good morning, Captain. Everything shipshape?
都準備好了，先生！ 但是我不是船長！
Shipshape it is, sir, but I'm not the captain.
船長在上面！
The captain's aloft.
埃柔先生，我已經
Mr. Arrow, I've checked
上上下下檢查過了
from stem to stern,
你怎麼都不會出點錯？
Can you get nothing wrong?
您過講了，船長
You flatter me, Captain.
啊，多普勒博士，我沒認錯吧？
Ah, Dr. Doppler, I presume?
哦，是的，我...
Uh, um, yes. I--
-你好啊，你能聽到我說話嗎？ -是的，我可以，不要再敲了！
-Hello! Can you hear me? -Yes, I can! Stop that banging!
博士，這東西使用時
If I may, Doctor, this works so much better...
可以工作的更好
when it's right-way up and plugged in.
-哦！ -你真是太可愛了！
-Ooh! -Lovely. There you go.
您要是不介意， 我想我可以自己來控制
If you don't mind, I can manage my own plugging!
我是阿米莉婭船長
I'm Captain Amelia...
普洛騰艦隊的後起之秀
Iate of a few run-ins with the Protean armada.
齷齪的買賣， 但我不想因我的創傷煩擾你
Nasty business, but I won't bore you with my scars.
您已經見過我的助手了 ——埃柔先生
You've met my first officer, Mr. Arrow.
淳樸，強壯，可靠， 誠實，勇猛，忠實
Sterling, tough, dependable, honest, brave, and true.
行了，船長
Please, Captain.
哦，閉嘴，埃柔！ 我是說你一樣都不是
Oh, shut up, Arrow. You know I don't mean a word of it.
啊哈，打擾一下。 我不喜歡打斷人家！
Ahem, excuse me. I hate to interrupt. It's not much better.
但是，我可以跟你們介紹， 吉姆·霍金斯
but may I introduce to you, Jim Hawkins?
吉姆，你們知道， 就是找到那些珍寶的男孩
Jim, you see, is the boy who found the treasure--
博士，夠了！
Doctor, please!
到我船艙來， 我跟你談談
I'd like a word with you in my stateroom.
博士，在這些多嘴的人面前
Doctor, to muse and blabber about the treasure now
說這些關於財寶的事情
in front of this particular crew...
只能說明
demonstrates a level of ineptitude...
你簡直就是一個低能兒
that borders on the imbecilic...
這麼說，我已經是很人道了
and I mean that in a very caring way.
低能？你這麼說我？ 愚蠢，我..
Imbecilic, did you say? Foolishness, I've--
我可以看看地圖嗎？
May I see the map, please?
看吧
Here.
呣，太好了
Hmm. Fascinating.
霍金斯先生，以後
Mr. Hawkins, in the future...
你可以叫我「船長」或者是「先生」
you will address me as "Captain" or "Ma'am."
明白了嗎？
Is that clear?
啊
Ugh...
霍金斯先生？
Mr. Hawkins?
-知道了，先生
-Yes, ma'am.
先生們，這東西不用的時候， 我們必須把它鎖起來
Gentlemen, this must be kept under lock and key...
博士，我用我最誠摯的敬意 再說一遍
when not in use. And, Doctor, again...with the greatest possible respect...
不要再大聲嚷嚷！
zip your howling screamer.
船長，我保證
Captain, I assure you l--
我簡短的說一下
Let me make this as monosyllabic as possible.
我不在乎你僱用的這些水手
I don't much care for this crew you hired.
他們...埃柔， 你說我要怎麼形容這些人？
They're...how did l describe them, Arrow?
早茶之前我說得很清楚了
I said something rather good this morning before coffee.
「一幫滑稽可笑的留著口水的傻子！」先生
"A ludicrous parcel of driveling galoots," ma'am.
-就是這樣！太有詩意了！ -現在，看著我
-There you go--poetry. -Now, see here--
博士，我想和所有的船員聊天
Doctor, I'd love to chat to the whole ship crew.
但是，我得負責這艘船的航行
but I have a ship to launch...
你也擦亮了你的裝備
and you've got your outfit to buff up.
埃柔先生，請你把這兩個新人
Mr. Arrow, please escort these two neophytes...
帶下去
down to the galley straightaway.
年輕的霍金斯就跟著 我們的廚師席爾瓦先生
Young Hawkins will be working for our cook, Mr. Silver.
什麼？廚師？
What? The cook?
死女人，屬貓的！
That woman! That...feline!
她搞清楚誰才是頭兒了沒有？
Who does she think is working for whom?
那是我的地圖， 她是拿我的工錢的！
It's my map, and she's got me bussin' tables?
不許你們說我船長的壞話！
I'll not tolerate a cross word about our captain!
再也找不到比她更好的長官了！
There's no finer officer in this or any galaxy.
席爾瓦先生？
Mr. Silver?
怎麼了？埃柔先生？
Why, Mr. Arrow, sir.
您的到來
Bringin' in such fine and distinguished gents...
使這裏蓬蓽生輝
to grace my humble galley.
您有何指示？
Had I known,
呵呵呵呵
Heh heh heh heh!
機器人！
A cyborg!
這是多普勒博士！
May I introduce Dr. Doppler?
我們此次航行的投資者
The financier of our voyage.
博士，您裝備很可愛
Lovely outfit, Doc.
哦，謝謝！ 您的眼睛也很不錯！
Well, thank you. Um, lovely eye.
這個小傢伙是吉姆·霍金斯
Uh, this young lad is Jim Hawkins.
吉姆！哦...
Jimbo! Uh...
啊，不要被這大傢伙嚇著了
Aw, now, don't be too put off by this hunk of hardware.
哇！
Whoa!
這裝置可以用來...
These gears have been tough getting used to...
但是他們的確很方便
but they do come in mighty handy from time to time.
呣！
Mmm!
好了，來，嘗嘗！
Here, now, have a taste
呣！我喜歡這味道， 濃烈的味道
Mmm! Delightfully tangy, yet robust.
祖傳秘方！
Old family recipe.
啊！
Aah!
實際上，那是祖傳秘方中的一部分！
In fact, that was part of the old family!
哈哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha!
歐歐歐！博士，我只是開個玩笑！
Oh, ho! I'm just kiddin', Doc!
哦，是的，沒事
Uh, yeah, well...
我要不開玩笑， 那不就是我了
I'm nothin' if I ain't a kidder.
喝吧，吉姆！
Go on, Jimbo. Have a swig.
墨菲！
Morph!
你這個淘氣的水滴！
You jiggle-headed blob of mischief!
你剛才藏哪兒去了？
So that's where you was hiding!
哇！哈！ 這是什麼？
Wha--? Ha! What is that thing?
「這是什麼？」
"What is that thing?"
他是個變種！
He's a morph.
我在變體1中裝了形狀轉換裝備
I rescued the little shape-shifter on Proteus 1.
啊哈，他看上我了
Aw, he took a shine to me.
我們一直在一起
We been together ever since.
好極了，啊，乖孩子
Right? Yeah. Nice boy.
走吧，我們下去吧
We're about to get underway.
博士，您要不要參觀一下這艘飛船？
Would you like to observe the launch, doctor?
我可以嗎？
Would l?
現在的星系核有超光速飛機嗎？
Does an active galactic nucleus have superluminal jets?
你帶路！
I'll follow you.
席爾瓦先生， 霍金斯先生留在這裏聽你的指示！
Mr. Hawkins will stay here in your charge, Mr. Silver.
先生，您能再說一遍嗎？
Beggin' your pardon, sir, but--
這是船長的命令， 別讓這個新來的服務生閒著！
Captain's orders! See to it the new cabin boy's kept busy.
-啊，但是不行...
-Aw, but, no, but--
這樣，船長讓你和我在一起？
So, Captain's put you with me, eh?
不管怎麼樣
Whatever.
我一個低賤的機器人 是不能和船長爭論的
Well, who be a humble cyborg to argue with a captain?
是的
Yeah.
你知道的，這些小狗
You know...these purps...
他們就像是 從蒙特裏莎回來的一樣
they're kind of like the ones back home on Montressor.
你去過那兒？
You ever been there?
吉姆，不能說是我去過
I can't say as I have, Jimbo.
仔細想想
Come to think of it,
我碰到這個老傢伙
I met this old guy, who was, um...
他在找他的機器人夥伴
he was kind of looking for a cyborg buddy of his.
是嗎？
Is that so?
是的
Yeah.
那人叫什麼名字？
What was that old salamander's name?
哦，哦，鮑恩斯
Oh, yeah. Bones.
比利·鮑恩斯？
Billy Bones?
鮑恩斯？鮑恩斯？
Bones? Bones?!
呣，他有搖鈴嗎？
Mm-mmm. T'ain't ringin' any bells.
一定是另外一個機器人！
Must have been a different cyborg.
在這艘船上還有許多機器人
There's a slew of cyborgs roamin' this port.
準備起飛！
Prepare to cast off!
哦，去吧，小伙子， 去看看起飛吧
Eh, off with you, lad, and watch the launch.
還有許多工作等著你做呢
There'll be plenty work a-waitin' for you afterwards.
我們最好盯著這個男孩， 是不是，墨菲？
We best be keepin' a sharp eye on this one, eh, Morph?
我們不能讓他多管閒事！
We wouldn't want him strayin' into things he shouldn't.
船長，我們都準備好了
We're all clear, Captain!
哦，朋友， 我們是不是可以讓這破船起飛了？
Well, my friend. Are we ready to raise this creaking tub?
船長，榮幸之至！
My pleasure, Captain.
各就各位！
All hands to stations!
快點！
Smartly now!
快點，你這個渣仔！ 我要追上你！
Come on, you scurvy scum! I'll race you!
打開所有太陽能帆！
Loose all solar sails!
快！
Come on!
把帆拉緊！
Heave up the braces.
拉緊！
Brace up.
哦，哦！
Ooh. Oh.
佐夫先生，加強船的吸引力
Mr. Zoff, engage the dropt
騰巴克先生，南偏西， 轉向：2－1－0－0
South by southwest, Mr. Turnbuckle, heading 2-1-0-0.
是，船長。2－1－0－0
Aye, Captain. 2-1-0-0.
全速前進。埃柔先生！
Full speed, Mr. Arrow, if you please.
全速前進！
Take her away!
博士，您能不能堅強一點？
Brace yourself, Doctor.
「您能不能堅強一點？」
"Brace yourself."
啊！哦！
Aah! Oof!
哇！
Whoa.
難以置信 這就是冥界的銀河？
Upon my word, an Orcus Galacticus.
笑一個
Smile.
哦，博士，你最好站遠點
Uh, Doctor, I'd stand clear--
哈
Ha.
啊，船長 真是航運史上一個偉大的日子
Ah. 'tis a grand day for sailing. Captain...
看看您
and look at you.
您衣冠楚楚，就像
You're as trim and as bonny as a sloop...
一艘上了新帆， 塗了新漆的帆船
with new sails and a fresh coat of paint.
席爾瓦先生， 你可以把你的這些恭維
You can keep that kind of flim-flammery...
送給那些在空間站的妓女
for your spaceport floozies, Silver.
飛船基地的妓女 飛船基地的妓女
Spaceport floozy, spaceport floozy--
船長，你也太打擊我了
You cut me to the quick, Captain.
我一直有什麼說什麼
I speaks nothing but me heart at all times.
自是肺腑之言
Nothing but me heart.
對了，那是你的幫手嗎？
And, by the way, isn't that your cabin boy...
在桅桿上閒逛的？
aimlessly footling about in those shrouds?
是的，他...哦
Yep, it--oh...
只是一時的失誤，船長！ 馬上就會恢復正常！吉姆！
A momentary aberration, Cap'n, soon to be addressed. Jimbo!
我新交了兩個朋友， 我想你見見他們
I got two new friends I'd like you to meet.
跟拖把先生和水桶小姐問好吧
Say hello to Mr. Mop and Mrs. Bucket.
呵呵呵呵！
Heh heh heh heh!
好啊
Yippee.
好了，我認識拖把先生了
Yeah, I got your Mr. Mop.
小心點，笨蛋
Watch it, twerp.
看什麼看，怪物！
What are you looking at, weirdo?
就是，怪物
Yeah, weirdo.
服務生要學會 專心干自己的事！
Cabin boys should learn to mind their own business.
為什麼？你把什麼東西藏起來了？ 亮眼睛的傢伙？
Why? You got something to hide, bright eyes?
看來你的耳朵有問題
Maybe your ears don't work so well.
是的，啊
Yeah. Ahem.
壞透了， 但是我的鼻子卻很正常
Too bad my nose works just fine.
什麼！你這個沒有家教的傢伙！
Why, you impudent little--
繼續，把他剁了！
Go ahead! Slice him! Dice him!
你再說一遍？服務生！
Any last words, cabin boy?
斯科洛先生
Mr. Scroop...
你知道
you ever see what happens to a fresh purp...
狗被用力掐的下場嗎？
when you squeeze real hard?
出什麼事了！
What's all this. then?
你們知道規矩的
You know the rules.
船上不許大聲喧嘩
There'll be no brawling on this ship.
是的，是的，先生
Aye, aye, sir.
以後誰要再犯，
Any further offenders will be confined to the brig...
就只能呆在狹窄的雙桅船裏了
for the remainder of the voyage.
斯科洛先生， 我說得夠明白嗎？
Am I clear, Mr. Scroop?
知道了
Transparently.
做的好，埃柔先生！
Well done, Mr. Arrow, sir!
一艘團結的船， 一艘令人愉快的船！
A tight ship's a happy ship, sir.
吉姆，給你個活幹！
Jimbo, I gave you a job.
嘿，之前我一直在做！
Hey, I was doing it until that bug thing--
閉嘴， 現在我要你把甲板拖的乾乾淨淨
Belay that! Now, I want this deck swabbed spotless...
我回來之前還沒做好， 你就祈求上帝保佑吧
and heaven help you if I come back and it's not done.
墨菲， 看著這小子
Morph? Keep an eye on this pup...
隨時留意著他有沒有分心
and let me know if there be any more distractions.
是，遵命！
OK. Aye-aye.
好了，大家都到齊了
So, we're all here, then.
-來了 -很好
-Excuse me. -Fine.
先生們，請原諒我的坦率
Now, if you pardon my plain speaking, gentlemen...
你們都是
are you all...
笨蛋， 徹徹底底的蠢貨嗎！？
stark-raving, totally blinking daft?!
我好不容易讓大家
After all me finagling getting us hired...
以水手的身份上船
as an upstanding crew...
你們想讓計劃全部敗露嗎？
you want to blow the whole mutiny before it's time?
那男孩已經有所察覺了！
The boy was sniffing about.
是你差點讓計劃失敗的，笨蛋！
You just stick to the plan, you bug-brained twit.
至於那個小孩， 我會給他一堆的活兒
As for the boy, I'll run him so ragged...
讓他沒有時間去想
he won't have time to think.
這真是有趣的一天
Well, this has been a fun day
交了新朋友，像那個蜘蛛
Making new friends like that spider psycho.
蜘蛛，蜘蛛
Spider psycho, spider psycho.
呵呵，有點醜
Heh. A little uglier.
哈哈哈哈
Mwah-ha-ha-ha!
閉上嘴吧
Pretty close.
哦
Well...
這真要感謝上帝了
thank heavens for little miracles.
上來一個小時了
Up here for an hour...
甲板還是老樣子
and the deck's still in one piece.
嗯，你知道，哦
Um, look, l, uh...
你所做的
What you did...
謝謝
Thanks.
難道沒人教你
Didn't your pap ever teach you...
要好好控制自己的情緒嗎？
to pick your fights a bit more carefully?
你父親沒有教你？
Your father's not the teachin' sort.
沒有！
No.
他離家出走了， 再也沒回來！
He was more the taking off and never coming back sort.
哦！
Oh.
對不起，小伙子
Sorry, lad.
嘿，沒事 我很好
Hey, no big deal. I'm doing just fine.
真的？
Is that so?
既然船長把你安排在我這裏
Well, since the captain has put you in my charge...
不管我喜不喜歡你
Iike it or not,
都不能讓你惹上麻煩
into that thick head of yours to keep you out of trouble.
-什麼？ -從現在起
-What? -From now on...
我會一直盯著你
I'm not letting you out of me sight.
你不能這麼做！
You can't do--
你不能想吃就吃 想睡就睡
You won't so much as eat, sleep...
沒我同意的話， 你什麼都不許做
or scratch your bum without my say-so.
你別在這兒給我出餿主意！
Don't do me any favors!
哦，小伙子， 你要相信我！
Oh, you can be sure of that, my lad.
相信我！
You can be sure of that.
哈哈哈哈！
Heh heh heh heh!
用點力氣
Put some elbow into it.
（歌詞） 愛通往神秘的地方
I am a question to the world
我不清楚的方向
Not an answer to be heard
跌跌撞撞，會不會魯莽
Or a moment that's held in your arms
星光照亮蒼白的天堂
And what do you think you'd ever say
燃燒膽怯的魔杖
I won't listen anyway
一股力量
You don't know me
在推著我體會冒險
And I'll never be what you want
的真相
Made of pain
勇敢口袋唯一的行囊
And what do you think you'd understand?
對抗沒落的權杖
I'm a boy. no. I'm a man
面對風暴絕對不投降
You can take me and throw me away
飛翔迎著空氣的冰涼
And how can you learn what's never shown
心卻越燒越滾燙
Yeah. you stand here on your own
這趟旅程不會一樣
They don't know me
寶藏葬在風暴的港灣
'Cause I'm not here
我在懷疑，我在想
And I want a moment to be real
不夠堅強，別和他較量
Want to touch things I don 't feel
寶藏，沒有清楚的模樣
Want to hold on and feel I belong
沒有真實的重量
And how can the world want me to change
依然發現終生難忘
They're the ones that stay the same
夥伴還有幾個在身旁
They don 't know me
同樣堅持和倔強
But I'm still here
不曾遺忘當初的信仰
And you see the things they never see
儘管路途遙遠而漫長
All you wanted. I could be
充滿未知和虛幻
Now you know me
只要記得
And I'm not afraid
你至誠的我在手上
And I want to tell you who I am
寶藏葬在風暴的港灣
Can you help me be a man?
我在懷疑，我在想
They can 't break me
不夠堅強，別和他較量
As long as I know who I am
寶藏，沒有清楚的模樣
They can 't tell me who to be
沒有真實的重量
'Cause I'm not what they see
依然發現終生難忘
Yeah. the world is still sleeping
手裏緊握藏寶圖
While I keep on dreaming for me
背誦你的祝福
城市一點點一點點
And the words are just whispers and lies
慢慢消失
That I'll never believe
勇氣漸漸的漸漸的
And I want a moment to be real
寫成故事
Want to touch things I don 't feel
寶藏葬在風暴的港灣
Want to hold on and feel I belong
哇！
Whoa!
我在懷疑我在想
How can you say I never change?
不夠堅強別和他較量
They're the ones that stay the same
寶藏沒有清楚的模樣
I'm the one now
沒有真實的重量
'Cause I'm still here
依然擁有終生難忘
I'm the one son still here
那寶藏是成長
I'm still here
是成長，是成長，在成長
哦，哦，哦！
Oh, ho ho!
你有麻煩了？
You having a little trouble there?
哦，離我遠點！
Oh, get away from me.
哦，吉姆
Oh, Jimbo.
我在你這年紀的時候要是會開船
If I could maneuver a skiff like that when I was your age...
那今天走街上， 他們都會向我鞠躬
they'd be bowing in the streets when I walked by today.
在街上鞠躬
Bowing in the streets.
-噢。 -噢。
-Oof. -Oof.
我不知道
I don't know.
我離開家的時候 他們並沒有對我表示讚揚。
They weren't exactly singing my praises when I left home.
-呵。喔。 -喔。
-Heh. Whew. -Whew.
但是我要改變這一切
But I'm gonna change all that.
現在？怎麼改變？
Are you now? How so?
哦，我有計劃。
Uh, I got some plans.
讓他們對我刮目相看
Gonna make people see me a little different.
哦
Ooh.
有時，人算不如天算
Sometimes, plans go astray.
這一次不會
Not this time.
呣
Hmm.
哦
Ooh...
歐，謝謝，墨菲
Oh, thank you, Morphy.
哦，為什麼
So, uh, how that happened anyway
你放棄了許多事情， 來實現一個夢想
You give up a few things chasing a dream.
值嗎？
Was it worth it?
呵
Heh.
我希望如此，吉姆
I'm hoping it is, Jimbo.
我一直堅信
I most surely am.
怎麼回事？
What the devil?
我的天
Good heavens.
是流星雨
The star Pelusa...
是超新星
it's gone supernova!
緊急迴避，騰巴克先生
Evasive action, Mr. Turnbuckle!
是 ，船長
Aye-aye, Captain.
所有人，把自己的救生索綁好了 各就各位
All hands,
埃柔先生，收帆
Mr. Arrow, secure those sails!
收帆
Secure all sails!
夥計們，把它們都收下來
Reef them down. men!
吔，寶貝！擊中了！ 哈哈哈哈！
Yeah, baby! Ba-boom! Ha ha ha ha!
-啊！ -席爾瓦！
-Aah! -Silver!
哇！謝謝！夥計！
Whoa. Thanks, lad.
船長，那顆星...
Captain, the star!
它飛向了一個...
It's devolving into a...
一個黑——洞！
a black hole!
我們就要被拉進去了！ 哦！
We're being pulled in! Ohh!
不，不行！
No, you don't, you--
這見鬼的波浪！ 他們太奇怪了！
Blast these waves! They're so deucedly erratic!
不，船長。 他們是有規律的！
No, Captain. They're not erratic at all.
四秒鐘之後還有一波！
There'll be one more in precisely 4  seconds.
後面還有一個更大的
Followed by the biggest magilla of them all!
當然，聰明的博士！
Of course! Brilliant, Doctor!
我們可以借助最後一波的衝力 離開這裏
We'll ride that last magilla out of here.
船長，帆都收好了！
All sails secured, Captain!
好樣的！ 現在把它們全部打開！
Good man! Now release them immediately!
遵命，船長！ 你們都聽到了，夥計們！
Aye, Captain. You heard her, men.
把帆全部展開
Unfurl those sails.
-什麼？！ -我們剛剛收起來！
-What?! -But we just finished...
-堅持住！ -一定要堅持住！
-Tying them down! -Make up your blooming minds!
霍金斯先生！
Mr. Hawkins...
確定所有救生索的結都打緊了！
make sure all lifelines are secured good and tight!
遵命，船長
Aye-aye, Captain.
很結實，船長！
Lifelines secured, Captain!
好極了！
Very good!
哇！啊——！
Gaah! Whoa!
喔！
Oof!
啊！
Aah!
船長，最後一波了！
Captain. the last wave!
它來了！
Here it comes!
先生們，抓緊你們的救生索！
Hold on to your lifelines, gents!
下面的航行會很顛簸！
It's gonna be a bumpy ride!
喔！
Oof!
船長！哦，我的天。那是..
Captain! That--oh, my goodness. That was--
那真是.. 那是最...
that was absolutely-- that was the most--
哦
Oh, tish-tosh.
你天文學的建議功勞最大了
your astronomical advice was most helpful.
哦，哦，謝謝。 非常感謝！
Well, uh, uh--thank you. Thank you very much.
哦，我可以在解剖學上提供幫助
Well, I have a lot of help to offer anatomically--
解剖學，解剖學
amanamonically-- as-astronomically.
對了，席爾瓦先生， 我該恭喜你
Well, I must congratulate you, Mr. Silver.
你的服務生男孩
It seems your cabin boy...
在救生索上做了很大貢獻啊
did a bang-up job with those lifelines.
所有人都做的很好
All hands accounted for,
埃柔先生？
Mr. Arrow?
我想埃柔先生失蹤了
I'm afraid Mr. Arrow has been lost.
他的救生索沒有綁緊
His lifeline was not secured.
不可能，我都檢查了
No, I checked them all.
我..我的確都檢查過了！ 他們都很牢靠！.
I--I did. I checked them all. They were secure.
我發誓！
I swear.
埃柔先生是個...
Mr. Arrow was a...
啊，很好的宇航員
Ahem. Fine spacer...
我們中最好的 是我們的榜樣
finer than most of us could ever hope to be...
他知道這有風險
but he knew the risks,
回到你們的崗位上， 我們繼續前進
Resume your posts. We carry on.
你知道嗎？ 那不是你的錯！
It weren't your fault, you know?
怎麼了，如果不是你 一半的人會被捲進黑洞的
Why, half the crew would be spinning in that black abyss--
你還不明白了嗎？ 是我把事情弄糟了
Look, don't you get it?! I screwed up!
只需兩秒鐘
For two seconds,
我本可以把事情做好，但是...
I could do something right, but--
啊！我只是...
Aagh! I just--
算了！算了！
Just forget it. Forget it.
現在，聽我說， 詹姆斯·霍金斯
Now, you listen to me, James Hawkins.
年輕人，雖然你有本事
You got the makings of greatness in ya...
但你必須為自己的理想掌舵
but you gotta take the helm and chart your own course.
好好努力
Stick to it,
機會來時
and when the time comes you get the chance...
你就可以檢驗自己所做的了
to really test the cut of your sails...
向他們展示你努力的成果 我希望我能看到
and show what you're made of, well, I hope I'm there...
抓住機會，你大有前途
catching some of the light coming off ya that day.
呵呵
There, there.
小伙子，好了，吉姆
Lad, it's all right, Jimbo.
好了
It's all right.
不，吉姆，哦...
Now, Jim, l, um...
我得去值班了
I best be getting about my watch...
你得回去睡覺了
and you best be getting some shut-eye.
我深陷其中了，墨菲
Getting in too deep here, Morphy.
他們會說我越來越心軟了
Next thing ya know, they'll be saying I've gone soft.
哦，歐！哦，歐！
Uh--oh! Oh! Ugh!
墨菲？
Morph?
墨菲，別鬧了 天還沒亮呢
Morph, knock it off. It's too early for this.
哦！嘿，墨菲！
Ow! Hey, Morph!
-嘿，回來！ -回來！
-Hey, come back here! -Come back here!
抓到你了，墨菲！
Gotcha, Morph!
夠了，小魷魚！
That's it, you little squid.
小魷魚！ 小魷魚！
You little squid. You little squid.
魷魚！魷魚！魷魚！魷魚！
Squid. Squid. Squid. Squid.
哦！哦！
Ungh! Unh!
哈！你完了！
Ha! Busted!
我們要說的是我們等不及了！
Look. what we're saying is we're sick of all this waiting.
他們只剩三個了！
There's only three of them left.
我們就等著行動了
We are wanting to move.
在拿到珍寶之前， 我們不能行動
We don't move till we got the treasure in hand.
我是說把他們全殺了
I say we kill 'em all now.
這裏我說的算！
I say what's to say!
埃柔先生已經死了
Disobey my orders again...
再違背我的命令
Iike that stunt you pulled with Mr. Arrow...
你的下場就和他一樣！
and so help me, you'll be joining him!
言重了， 我知道
Strong talk, but I know otherwise.
斯科洛，你要說什麼？
You got something to say. Scroop?
那個男孩
It's that boy.
我發現你對他很溫柔
Methinks you have a soft spot for him.
是啊
Yeah.
現在，看著我，你們
Now, mark me, the lot of ya.
我只關心一件事， 只有一件事！
I care about one thing, and one thing only!
弗林特的寶藏！
Flint's trove.
你們以為我會因為
You think I'd risk it all for the sake...
這個小孩子，放棄嗎？
of some nose-wiping little whelp?
那現在怎麼辦？
What was it now?
你在這年輕人身上投入了太多
"Oh. you got the makings of greatness in ya. "
閉嘴！
Shut your yap!
我只是讓他愜意， 不至於察覺我們的事情
I cozied up to that kid to keep him off our scent.
我不會心軟
But I ain't gone soft.
發現大陸了
Land ho!
哈哈哈，就在那裏
Ha ha ha! There it is!
你們到了那裏 就可以一飽眼福了
Feast eyes and click heels if you got 'em.
我的望遠鏡呢？
Where the devil's me glass?
吉姆
Jimbo.
我們在捉迷藏？
Playing games, are we?
是的
Yeah.
是的，我們是在捉迷藏
Yeah, we're playing games.
哦，我明白了， 好了，我從不放棄
Oh, I see. Well, I was never
我討厭失敗
Always hated to lose.
呣
Hmm.
我也是！
Me, too!
啊——！
Yaaah!
右邊
Right-o...
哦，計劃全亂了
Ohh...blast it all.
夥計們，計劃有變
Change in plan, lads!
現在馬上行動
We move now!
掛上我們的旗幟，奧訥斯先生
Strike our colors, Mr. Onus.
非常高興，船長先生
With pleasure, Captain.
我船上有海盜？ 我要殺光他們！
Pirates on my ship? I'll see they all hang.
博士，會玩這東西嗎？
Doctor, familiar with these?
哦，我見過
Oh, I've seen--
哦，不不不，我不會
Uh, no. No. No, I'm not.
哦
Ooh.
霍金斯先生，你死都要保住它
Mr. Hawkins! Defend this with your life.
墨菲，把它給我
Morph! Give me that!
哦，你們已經等了很久了
Oh, you're taking all day about it.
哦，攔住他們
Oh! Stop them!
啊，啊，啊喔！
Aah, aah, aah. Oof!
喔呼
Ooh hoo hoo!
嘿，你！
Hey, you!
到艇上去，快！
To the longboats, quickly!
啊！
Unh!
吔！
Rrr-yeah!
墨菲，不要！
Morph! No!
看這邊！
Chew on this,
你瞄準了打的？
Did you actually aim for that?
實際上，我的確瞄準了！
You know, actually, I did.
哦，完了
Oh, blast it.
博士，我說「現在」的時候 把前面那纜繩打斷
Doctor, when I say "now", shoot out the forward cable.
放心吧，我做得到
I'll take this one.
墨菲，這裏，墨菲
Morph. here! Morph!
墨菲！
Morph!
墨菲，過來！
Morphy, come here.
墨菲，墨菲，過來！ 墨菲，過來
Morph. Morph. Bring it here. Morph, come here.
過來，過來，乖！ 回到父親這裏！.
Come here. Come here, boy. Come to your dad.
墨菲，過來
Come here, boy. Morph!
-過來這邊！ -墨菲，墨菲，這裏！
-Come on! -Morph! Morph, here!
-墨菲！ -墨菲！
-Morphy! -Morph!
歐！
Ohh.
現在！
Now!
哇！
Whoa!
啊！
Unh!
吉姆！
Jim!
參數正確 水力學派上用場了
Parameters met. Hydraulics engaged.
找到了，來爸爸這吧
That's it! Come to papa!
不要開炮！ 地圖在他們身上！
Hold your fire! We'll lose the map!
船長！ 激光球在12點鐘方向！
Captain! Laser ball at 12 o'clock!
-哇！ -啊！
-Whoa! -Aah!
哦
Ow.
哦，我的天
Oh, my goodness.
太好玩了， 我都想再來一次
That was more fun than I ever want to have again.
這不是我最成功的著陸！
That's not one of my...gossamer landings. Unh!
船長！
Captain!
哦！
Oh. Ooh.
哦，不要大驚小怪！
Oh, don't fuss.
哦
Uh-uh--
只是小傷，沒事
Slight bruising. That's all.
來杯茶， 我馬上就會好了
Cup of tea, and I'll be right as rain.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins.
把地圖給我
The map if you please.
啊
Ah.
墨菲
Morph!
墨菲，地圖呢？
Morph, where's the map?!
你說真的？！它還在船上？？？
Are you serious?! It's back on the ship?
讓那水滴別再吵了
Stifle that blob and get low.
我們的夥伴來了
We've got company.
我們得找個好地方防守
We need a more defensible position.
霍金斯先生，前面探路
Mr. Hawkins, scout ahead.
遵命，船長
Aye, Captain.
-哦！ -小心點，小心點！
-Unh! -Steady, steady.
現在，看看這個
Now, let's have a look at that.
噓——
Shh. shh.
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
哦，真是太神奇了
Oh, this is fantastic!
終於來了一個 炭組織結構的東西來救我了
A carbon-based life form come to rescue me at last!
我只是想擁抱你
I just want to hug you and squeeze you...
把你抱得緊緊的
and hold you close to me.
好了，你還讓不讓我走？
All right. OK. Would you just let go of me?
哦，對不起，對不起，對不起！
Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
我已經一個人很久了
It's just I've been marooned for so long.
我是說，孤獨真好
I mean, solitude's fine.
已經幾百年了
For hundreds years
你滾遠點 哈哈哈
you go a little nuts! Ha ha ha!
對不起，是不是我...
I'm sorry. Am l...
我，嗯...
I am, um...
我叫..
My name is, uh...
本！是了，我叫本
B.E.N.! Of course, I'm B.E.N.
生物電子學航海家
Bioelectronic Navigator. Oops.
-你是？ -吉姆
-And you are? -Jim.
哦，很高興見到你，吉米
Oh, what a pleasure to meet you, Jimmy.
-是吉姆 -無論如何...
-It's Jim. -Anyway...
你看，我是個...
Look, I'm kind of
我想找個可以藏身的地方， 有海盜在追我
I got to find a place to hide, and there's pirates chasing me.
哦，海盜！ 別讓我見到海盜！
Oh, pirates! Don't get me started on pirates!
我不喜歡他們！ 我記得弗林特船長。
I don't like them. I remember Captain Flint.
這傢伙火氣太大了
This guy had such a temper.
等等，你認識弗林特船長？
Wait, wait, wait. You knew Captain
我想他經常情緒起伏不定
I think he suffered from mood swings, personally.
我不是個醫學家
I'm not a therapist, and anyway...
但我..我在散步的時候認識了你
but l--you let me know when I'm rambling.
就是說...
But that means--but wait.
你知道財寶的事？
But then you gotta know about the treasure?
-財寶？ -是的，弗林特的寶藏？
-Treasure? -Yeah, Flint's trove?
你知道的， 從幾千個世界掠奪來的戰利品
You know,
那是，那是...
It's--well, it's...
有那麼一點點.. 一點點印象
it's all a little-- little--little fuzzy.
等等，我想起來了
Wait. I--I r-r-remember.
是的，我...財寶
I do. I--treasure!
許許多多的財寶埋在
Lots of treasure buried in the centroid--
那些機械裝置的核心
centroid--centroid of the mechanism.
有一個大門 開開關關
And there was this big door opening and closing...
開開關關
and opening and closing...
弗林特船長要確定
and Captain Flint wanted to make sure...
沒人可以找到他的財寶
nobody could ever get to his treasure...
所以，我幫了他
so I helped him...
啊！數據錯誤！重新啟動！
Aah! Data inaccessible! Reboot!
本？本？本！ 重新啟動....
B.E.N.? B.E.N.? B.E.N.!
重新啟動！啊！你是？
Reboot! Aah! And you are?
等等，財寶怎麼樣了？
Wait, wait, wait!
我要說，拉裏
I want to say Larry.
機械裝置的核心...
The--the centroid of the mechanism, or--
對不起，我的內存已經改變
I'm sorry. My memory isn't what it used to be.
我都忘了，哈哈！ 我都忘了！
I've lost my mind. Ha ha! I've lost my mind.
你有沒有找到它？
You haven't found it, have you?
哦，我丟了的那一塊？ 我的主存儲器電路？
Uh, my missing piece? My primary memory circuit?
本，我真的要 找一個可以藏身的地方？OK？
Look, B.E.N., I really need to find a place to hide, OK?
所以，我只是想， 你知道的，繼續前進
So I'm just gonna be, you know, moving on.
哦，哦，好了，那...
Oh, uh, so, well, then...
我想這就是分別了？
I guess, uh... this is good-bye, huh?
我對我程序紊亂表示道歉
I'm sorry that I'm so dysfunctional.
好了，你走你的吧 我明白
So, uh, go ahead and... I do understand.
我明白，再見
I do. Bye-bye.
好了，你要是不想一個人呆著
Look, if you're gonna come along...
你就不要再說什麼了
you're gonna have to stop talking.
嗚呼！哈哈哈！ 真是太好了
Huzzah! Ha ha ha! Oh, this is fantastic!
我和我最好的夥伴要找一個...÷
Me and my best buddy are lookin' for a...
小聲點
Being quiet.
你以後不要再碰我
And you have to stop touching me.
以後我都不許 碰你，跟你說話！
Touching and talking. That's my two big no-nos.
好了，現在，我想...
OK. Now, I think
聽著，在我們開始找之前
Say, listen, before we go out on our big search...
嗯，您是不是先看看我的地方？
um, would you mind if we made a quick pit stop at my place?
挺急迫的，呵呵
Kind of urgent.
本，我想這正是我想要的
I think you just solved my problem.
不好意思，我這裏那麼亂
Uh. pardon the mess. people.
你們可以想像， 這一百多年來
You'd think in a hundred years...
這裏佈滿了灰塵
I would've dusted a little more often...
但是，你們住進來了
but, you know, when you're batchin' it...
我會收拾好的
you tend to, uh, let things go.
啊，真是太可愛了
Aw, isn't that sweet?
我發現過去流行的羅曼史是那麼動人！
I find old-fashioned romance so touching, don't you?
我們是不是要為 這對快樂的夫妻喝一杯？
How about drinks for the happy couple?
哦，哦，哦！不！
Oh, uh, ooh. Uh, no.
謝謝，我們不喝酒
Thank you, we don't drink...
還有，我們不是夫妻
and, uh, we're not a couple.
啊哈，看這些標記
Ahem. Look at these markings.
和地圖上的一模一樣
They're identical to the ones on the map.
我猜想這是遠古文化中 的象形文字留下來的
I suspect these are the hieroglyphic remnants...of an ancient culture.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins...
別讓任何人靠近
stop anyone who tries to approach. Ohh!
是的，是的，現在聽我說
Yes, yes. Now listen to me...
不要操心指揮的事， 安靜的躺一會兒
stop giving orders for a few milliseconds and lie still.
不錯的建議，博士
Very forceful, Doctor.
繼續，說點別的
Go on. Say something else.
嘿，看那兒，還有幾個你們的朋友
Hey. Iook! There's some more of your buddies!
嗨，夥計們！ 我們在這兒！
Hey, fellas! We're over here, fellas!
哦哦哦！
Oh! Uhh! Ooh! Ohh!
不要浪費子彈！
Stop wastin' your fire!
你們好啊，上面的人！
Hello. up there!
吉姆？
Jimbo?
你和船長他們都好嗎？
If it's all right with the captain...
我跟你說句話
I'd like a short word with ya.
不是圈套
No tricks,
肯定是衝著地圖來的
Come to bargain for the map, doubtless.
這個垃圾...
Pestilential...
-啊！ -船長
-Ugh! -Captain.
那就是說， 他還以為地圖在我們手上？
That means...that he thinks we still have it.
啊，墨菲， 我還以為你跑哪兒去了呢
Ah, Morphy! I wondered where you was off to.
哦
Ooh.
哦，這條老腿
Oh, this poor old leg's downright snarky...
我們在船上的那次 捉迷藏之後就不中用了
since that game attack we had in the galley.
啊
Ahh.
無論你在那裏聽到了什麼
Whatever you heard back there...
至少那些關於你的
at least the part concerning you...
我說的都是實話
I didn't mean a word of it.
那些殘忍的傢伙 都認為我變的心軟了
Had that bloodthirsty lot thought I'd gone soft...
他們會把我們兩個都殺了
they'd have gutted us both.
聽著，如果我們處理得當
Listen to me. If we play our cards right...
有了這些錢， 我們可以去當國王了
we can both walk away from this rich as kings.
-是嗎？ -呵呵呵
-Yeah? -Ha ha ha.
你把地圖給我
You get me that map...
哦
and, uh...
財寶中的很大一部分， 就是你的了
an even portion of the treasure is yours.
孩子
Boy.
你在船上說的那些 冠冕堂皇的話都是真心的嗎？
You are really something.All that talk of greatness...
讓我看到了希望... 呵呵，真是可笑
Iight coming off my sails... what a joke.
看著我，吉姆
Now, just see here, Jimbo--
我想，至少
I mean, at least
要堅持下去，是不是？
Stick to it, right?
對了，那就是我要做的
Well, that's just what I'm gonna do.
我會讓你永遠看不到
I'm gonna make sure that you never see...
我的那些財寶
one drabloon of my treasure!
那些財寶是屬於我的！
That treasure is owed me,
好了，那你就試著 不要用我的地圖，去找到它吧
Well, try to find it without my map, by thunder!
哦，你還不知道 怎麼發揮你的鬥志是不是？
Oh, you still don't know how to pick your fights, do you, boy?
好，看著我
Now, mark me.
你有兩個選擇： 天亮之前把地圖給我
Either I get that map by dawn tomorrow...
或是協助我， 否則，我會用船上的大炮
or so help me, I'll use the ship's cannons...
把你們炸爛！
to blast ya all to kingdom come!
墨菲，跟我走
Morph, hop to it.
馬上過來！
Now!
哦，見鬼！
Oh, blast it!
先生們
Gentlemen...
我們必須呆在一起， 還有...
we must stay together and...
還有...哦
and...ohh.
還有什麼？什麼？
And what? What?!
我們必須呆在一起， 還有什麼？
We must stay together and what?!
博士，你的眼睛真迷人
Doctor,
她已經神智不清了
She's lost her mind!
哦，你應該趕緊幫幫她
Well, you gotta help her.
該死，吉姆，我是個 天文學家，不是醫生
Dang it, Jim. I'm an astronomer, not a doctor.
我是說，我是個博士
I mean, I am a doctor,
我有博士頭銜， 但那不是一回事兒
I have a doctorate. It's not the same thing.
這博士頭銜救不了人
You can't help people with a doctorate.
你怎麼只是坐在那裏， 也不來幫忙？
You just sit there, and you're useless.
好了，博士
It's OK, Doc.
沒事的
It's all right.
是的，博士！ 吉姆知道怎麼離開這裏。
Yeah, Doc! Jimmy knows exactly how to get out of this.
只有吉姆能想到這些辦法
It's just Jimmy has this knowledge of things.
吉姆，有主意了嗎？
Jim, any thoughts at all?
沒有地圖，我們就完蛋了
Without the map, we're dead.
我們想要逃走， 肯定是死
If we try to leave, we're dead.
-呆在這裏... -我們死定了
-lf we stay here-- -We're dead!
我們死定了！我們死定了！
We're dead! We're dead!
好了，我想吉姆要靜下來想想。
Well, I think that Jimmy could use a little quiet time. Heh.
所以，我要從後門出去了
So I'll just slip out the back door.
-後門？ -是的
-Back door? -Oh, yeah.
我從這兒可以輕鬆逃走
I get this delightful breeze through here...
我想這很重要
which I think is important...
因為在朋友之間活動...
because ventilation among friends--
哇，這是什麼？
Whoa. What is all this stuff?
你是說那些遠處的機器
You mean the miles and miles of machinery that run...
在行星中是怎麼運轉的嗎？
through the entire course of the inside of this planet?
你在說什麼？
Not a clue.
博士，博士， 我想我找到出口了
Hey, Doc! Doc! I think I found a way out of here!
不，不，吉姆，等等 船長讓我們呆在一起
No, no. Jim, wait.
-我會回來的 -衝啊！
-I'll be back. -Cannonball!
嗚呼！
Woof.
-有什麼計劃？ -噓，本，安靜！
-So, what's the plan? -Shh. B.E.N., quiet.
好了，是這樣
OK, here it is.
我們偷偷回到船上， 毀掉激光炮
We sneak back to the Legacy, disable the laser cannons...
把地圖帶回來
and bring back the map.
計劃聽起來很不錯
That's a good plan.
我喜歡。 只是..
I like that plan. The only thing is...
我想我們要怎麼回去？
I'm wondering, how do we get there?
用那個
On that.
哦
Ooh.
Oop?
啊！ -本，噓！
Aah! -B.E.N.. shh!
對不起，對不起，對不起
Sorry. sorry. Sorry.
好了，我去拿地圖， 你呆在這裏！
OK, I'll get the map. You wait here.
收到，吉米。 我會看著激光炮的！
Roger, Jimmy. I'll neutralize laser cannons, sir!
本！本！
B.E.N.! B.E.N.!
喲呼，喲呼 我也過上海盜生活了
Yo-ho. yo-ho. a pirate's life for me
破壞激光炮。 我應該怎麼做呢？
Disable a few laser cannons. What is the big deal?
我要做的只是找到那條線
All we gotta do is find that one little wire.
哦，我的媽
Oh, mama.
就是你了
Yes.
壞了，本，壞事了
Bad, B.E.N. Bad.
好了，修好了
OK, fixing.
那愚蠢的機器人 會害死我們的
That stupid robot's gonna get us all...killed.
服務生！
Cabin boy.
啊！
Aah!
喔，OK，不著急
Whoops. OK. don't panic.
吸氣，呼氣
Breathing in... breathing out...
-啊！ -呣？
-Aah! -Hmm?
啊！
Raah!
這條應該是激光炮的了
This has gotta be cannons.
完了，不是
Maybe not.
啊！
Rraar!
呵呵
Heh heh.
過來，過來，過來
Come on, come on, come on.
不！
No!
哦，好極了！
Oh, yes.
記得跟埃柔先生問好
Do say hello to Mr. Arrow.
啊！
Rraar!
你自己跟他說吧！
Tell him yourself!
啊——！
Aah!
給我回去， 你這淘氣的插頭！
Back you go, you naughty plug! Oh!
哦！
Unh!
墨菲？
Morph?
激光炮已經破壞
Laser cannons disconnected...
吉米船長！
Captain Jimmy, sir!
並不是很難
Gee, that wasn't so tough.
博士，博士！醒醒！
Doc! Doc, wake up!
我找到地圖了
I got the map.
幹得好，吉姆 謝謝你幫我
Fine work, Jimbo.
孩子，謝謝你幫我們找到那條路
Thanks for showing us the way, boy.
啊！
Aah!
這堆爛鐵是什麼玩意兒？
What's this sorry stack of metal?!
不要碰我的臉！
Not the face!
吉姆，你跟我一樣
You're just like me, Jimbo.
你討厭失敗
Ya hates to lose.
怎麼回事？
What the devil's the...
打開它
Open it.
我得開始工作了
I'd get busy.
看到沒，多麼神奇啊
Oh, the powers that be. Would you look?
哈哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha!
綁緊他讓他們一起呆著， 直到我們...什麼？
Tie him up and leave him with the others till we--what?
你要地圖
You want the map...
就把我帶上
you're taking me, too.
呣
Hmm.
把他們都帶走
We'll take 'em all.
哦
Unh.
沒事，墨菲，沒事的
It's OK, Morph. It's OK.
吉米，我不知道你為什麼...
Jimmy, l--I don't know about you...
我看到我的一生在我眼前滑過
but I'm starting to see my life pass in front of my eyes.
至少，那是我的一生
At least, I think it's my life.
我和一個叫著盧皮的機器人跳過舞？
Was I ever dancing with an android named Lupe?!
本，噓
B.E.N., shh.
還沒完
This isn't over yet.
夥計們，我們越來越靠近了
We're gettin' close. Iads.
我聞到了財寶的味道... 它就在前面
I smell treasure a-waitin'.
哦？
Huh?
在哪兒？
Where is it?
我什麼都沒看到！ 狗屎，怎麼什麼都沒有？
I see nothing! One great, big stinking hunk of nothing!
怎麼回事，吉姆？
What's going on, Jimbo?
我不知道， 我打不開了
I don't know. I can't get it open.
我們早就不該跟著這小子了！
We should've never followed this boy!
嘿！
Hey!
我勸你最好
I'd suggest you get...
把那東西弄好！快點！
that gizmo going again. and fast!
把他殺了，剖開他的肚子！
Let's rip his gizzard right out right now!
把他從山崖上扔下去！
Throw him off the cliff!
哦，原諒他吧
Oh, have mercy.
星雲圖？
The Lagoon Nebula?
那只是星系中的一部分
But that's halfway across the galaxy.
有個大門
A big door...
開開關關
opening and closing.
讓我看看
Let's see.
金納皮斯（地名）
Kinapis.
蒙特裏莎空間站
Montressor spaceport.
弗林特就是這麼做的
So that's how Flint did it.
他用這個入口 到世界各地去掠奪財寶的！
He used this portal to roam the universe stealing treasure.
他把它們都藏到哪兒去了呢？
But where'd he stash it all?
那個該死的財寶在哪兒？
Where's that blasted treasure?!
財寶！財寶！
Treasure! Treasure!
它被埋在...
It's buried in the--
埋在機器的中央核心處
Buried in the centroid of the mechanism.
如果這個行星就是那個機器
What if the whole planet is the mechanism...
財寶就埋在行星的中央
and the treasure is buried in the center of this planet?
太令人失望了， 我們怎麼樣才能到那裏？
And how in blue blazes are we supposed to get there?
只要打開右邊的門就可以了
Just open the right door.
等等我！等等我！
Wait for me! Wait for me!
從數千個世界掠奪來的戰利品
The loot of a thousand worlds.
我們要一隻更大的船！
We are going to need a bigger boat!
這怎麼看起來這麼眼熟？
This is all seeming very familiar.
為什麼？
I can't remember why.
本，跟我來
B.E.N., come on.
我們離開這裏， 但不能空手離開
We're getting out of here, and we're not leaving empty-handed.
但是，但是，吉米，吉米！
But--but, Jimmy! Jimmy!
我這一生的追求
A lifetime of searching.
最後
And at long last...
我終於找到了
I can touch it.
你沒覺得奇怪嗎？
Do you know what's strange?
我沒法阻止這件事情發生，吉米
I can't tell you how frustrating this is, Jimmy...
因為有些想法...
'cause there's something just--
在我的腦子裏盤旋不去
it's nagging at the back of my mind.
啊！
Aah!
-弗林特船長？ -還是個人形！
-Captain Flint? -ln the flesh!
哦，還保持完好
Well, s-sort of,
或者說是像個人形
or anything that--that--that resembles flesh...
不是的
that's not there.
怎麼這麼奇怪？ 你看出來了嗎？
And yet it's so odd. you know?
我記得有些很恐怖的事
I remember there was something horrible...
弗林特不想任何人知道...
Flint didn't want anyone else to know...
但是我就是想不起來是什麼
but I--I just can't remember what it was.
哦，一件很恐怖的事情...
Oh, a mind
本，我想我找到你的腦子了
B.E.N.,
別動
Hold still.
啊！吉米，你的手太冰了
Aah! Jimmy, your hands are very, very cold.
哇！
Whoa!
你好啊
Hello.
哦，吉米，我在想...
You know, uh, Jimmy, I was just thinking...
我在想...
I was just think--
我的記憶全回來了
It's all flooding back! All my memories!
對了，弗林特把我的存儲器電路拔下來
Right up until Flint pulled my memory circuits...
我就無法告訴 別人他設下的陷阱！
so I could never tell anybody about his booby trap!
-說什麼？ -啊？
-Speaking of which... -Huh?
弗林特要保證...
Flint wanted to make sure...
沒人可以偷走他的財寶
that nobody could ever steal his treasure...
所以，他控制了整個行星
so he rigged this whole planet...
它會把你炸得比卡勒希安風箏還高
to blow higher than a Kalepsian kite!
快跑，吉米！快逃命吧！
Run, Jimmy! Run for your life!
你回去幫船長和博士！
You go back and help the captain and Doc!
如果我5分鐘之後還沒回去 你們就先走
If I'm not there in 5 minutes,
我不會離開我的朋友，吉米
I am not leaving my buddy Jimmy.
除非他這麼看著我
Unless he looks at me like that.
再見，吉姆
Bye, Jim!
不！不！哦！不！哦！不！
No! No! Oh, no! Oh, no!
不！啊！
No! Aah!
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
回來，笨蛋！
Come back here, ya blighters!
我這一生都想要 一次像這樣的冒險
All my life, I dreamed of an adventure like this.
哦，對不起
I'm just sorry...
我不能好好的幫你
I couldn't have been more helpful to you.
哦，別傻了
Oh, don't be daft.
其實，你已經幫了我很多
You've been very helpful. Truly.
我覺得自己就像 一個無能的傢伙
I feel like such a useless weakling...
我沒用多大勁啊
with abnormally thin wrists.
對不起，海盜先生
Excuse me, brutish pirate.
對了，就是你，我有個問題
Yes, you. I have a question.
你的身材對於你那小小的腦袋
Is it that your body is too massive...
是不是太過於臃腫了？
for your teeny-tiny head...
或者說是你的腦袋對於你壯碩的身軀
or is it that your head is too teeny-tiny...
太過渺小了？
for your big, fat body?
我要好好教訓你！
I pummel you good!
是的，我想你會這麼做的。 但這之前
Yes, I'm sure you will, but before you do...
我還有一個問題。 這是你的嗎？
I have one more question. Is this yours?
哦
Uhh...
是的！墨菲， 我們就要出去了！
Yes! Morph, we are so out of here!
啊，吉姆！
Ah. Jimbo!
你真是世界的第七大奇跡！
Aren't you the seventh wonder of the universe?
退回去！
Get back!
我喜歡你，小伙子 我遠道而來
I like you, lad, but I've come too far...
你卻阻擾我拿回我的財寶
to let you stand between me and me treasure.
啊！
Aah!
哦，不，哦，不要！
Oh, no, you don't!
什麼？
What?
吉姆
Jimbo.
抓住了
Reach for me now!
抓住！
Reach!
我...我夠不著！
I--I can't!
啊！
Aah!
我...
I...
哦，我簡直就是個瘋子！
Oh, blast me for a fool!
啊！
Aah!
席爾瓦，你放棄了？
Silver, you gave up?
它困擾了我一生，吉姆！ 我會克服的！
Just a lifelong obsession, Jim. I'll get over it.
歡迎你回來，吉米！
Aloha. Jimmy!
快點！只剩2分34秒
Hurry, people! We got exactly two minutes...
行星就要爆炸了
and thirty-four seconds till planet's destruction!
做的很好，博士
You're doing fine, Doctor.
現在讓它放鬆一點， 慢慢來，慢慢來！
Now ease her over gently--gently!
啊！我們呆在行星上都比這好
Aah! We were better off on exploding planet!
趕緊讓我們離開這裏，金屬人！
Take us out of here, metal man!
遵命，船長
Aye, Captain!
船長，你簡直就是神女下凡...
Captain, you dropped from the heavens in the nick of--
把討好的話跟法官說吧，席爾瓦
Save your claptrap for the judge, Silver!
導彈尾部被破壞了
Missile tail demobilized,
推進器只剩30％的能量
Thrusters at only 30% of capacity.
30％？就是說，我們...
30%? That means we're--
我們無法在行星爆炸之前離開了
We'll never clear the planet's explosion in time.
-調頭回去。 -什麼？
-We gotta turn around. -What?
那裏有個入口， 我們可以從那裏離開
There's a portal back there. It can get us out of here!
對不起，吉姆。 那個入口還沒打開
Pardon me. Jim. but didn't that portal open...
回到火一般的地獄？
onto a raging inferno?!
是的，我要把更改入口
Yes, but I'm gonna change that.
打開另外一個門
I'm gonna open a different door.
船長，真的嗎？ 我覺得那太不可思議
Captain, really, I don't see how this is possible--
照著他說的做
Listen to the boy!
離行星爆炸還有1分20秒
One minute, twenty-nine seconds till planet's destruction!
-我們還要怎麼做？吉姆？ -想想怎麼綁住這東西！
-What do you need, Jim? -Just some way to attach this.
好的，後退，後退一點！
All right. Stand back. Stand back, now.
可以走了
There you go.
好了，不管發生什麼
OK. Now,
把飛船直接衝向入口
keep the ship heading straight for that portal.
還剩58秒
Fifty-eight seconds!
好了，你們聽到他說的了
Well, you heard him!
調頭
Get this blasted heap turned 'round!
博士，把船頭對準入口
Doctor,
遵命，船長
Aye, Captain.
向右，右邊！
Go to the right! The right!
我知道，我知道！ 我只是在試試
I know, I know!
25秒！
Twenty-five seconds!
不！不！
No! No!
加油，小伙子！
Come on, lad.
17秒！
Seventeen seconds!
7...
Seven...
6...5...4...
six... five... four...
3...2...
three...two...
哇！吔！
Wow! Y eah!
你成功了，吉米！
You done it. Jimmy!
你成功了！哈哈哈！
You done it, boy! Ha ha ha!
我早說過了這孩子很出色！
Didn't I say the lad had greatness in him?
太好了
Unorthodox,
我很榮幸把你推薦給
I'd be proud to recommend you...
星際學院， 他們需要一個像你這樣的人
to the interstellar academy. They could use a man like you.
等著吧， 你媽媽聽到這個肯定很高興！
Just wait until your mother hears about this!
那當然，我們不用再為生計犯愁了
Of course, we may downplay the life-threatening parts.
吉米，這真是終生難忘的時刻
Jimmy, that was unforgettable!
我知道你不喜歡我碰你
I know you don't like touching...
但是，準備好， 我要好好的擁抱你
but get ready for a hug, big guy, 'cause I gotta hug ya!
哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha ha!
嘿，你也回過來抱我了
Hey, you hugged me back.
哦，我發誓不再哭的
Oh, I promised myself I wouldn't cry.
你們誰有紙巾？
Does anyone have a tissue?
-墨菲，我們做標記！ -我知道
-Morphy, we gotta make tracks. -I know.
你不會離開的，是不是？
You never quit. do you?
啊，吉姆！哈哈
Ah, Jimbo! Ha ha!
我只是檢查一下，看看...
I was merely checking to make sure...
看看我們最後 一艘船是不是完好無損！
our last longboat was safe and secure.
呣！
Mmm.
哦
Well...
應該綁緊了
that should hold it.
呵呵，我教得很好啊
Heh heh heh. I taught you too well.
如果你不介意， 我可不想進監獄
If you don't mind, we'd just as soon avoid prison.
小墨菲在這裏自由自在
Little morphy here, he's a free spirit.
關在籠子裏， 它會很傷心的
Being in a cage, it'd break his heart.
哦！
Ohh!
小伙子，跟我一起走吧
What say you ship out with us, lad?
你和我
You and me,
只有我們，沒人約束我們
full of ourselves and no ties to anyone!
你知道
You know,
我原本會和你一起走的
I would've taken you up on that offer in a second...
但是，哦，我有一個很好的朋友
but, uh,
但是他教過我， 我可以規劃我的一生
and he taught me that I could chart my own course.
那正是我要做的
That's what I'm gonna do.
那你怎麼看你的那個朋友？
And what do you see of that pal of yours?
是將來
A future.
為什麼？
Why...
看看你，充滿了活力
Iook at ya, glowing like a solar fire.
你會很出色的，吉姆
You're something special, Jim.
你會很有成就的
You're gonna rattle the stars, you are.
我的機器眼睛要加點潤滑油了
Got a bit of grease in this cyborg eye of mine.
哦，嘿，墨菲， 我們還會再見的，OK？
Oh, hey, Morph. I'll see ya around, OK?
還會再見的！
See ya around.
墨菲，我要你做件事！
Morphy, I got a job for ya.
你給我好好盯著這個小子
I need you to keep an eye on this here pup.
你願意幫我嗎？
Will ya do me that little favor?
遵命，船長！
Aye-aye, Captain.
哦，還有件事
Oh, and one more thing.
這是給你媽媽的
This is for your dear mother...
讓她重建她的旅館！
to rebuild that inn of hers.
別再惹麻煩了，老傢伙！
Stay out of trouble, ya old scalawag.
哈哈，吉姆，小伙子
Why, Jimbo, lad...
我做過什麼嗎？
when have I ever done otherwise?
哦！
Oh!
（歌詞） 沐浴著陽光，我沉醉在這裏的一切
It's good to see the sun and feel this place
從未有如此強烈的家的感覺
This place I never thought would feel like home
我膽怯
And I ran forever
遠遠逃離
Far away
總以為我要在這裏孤獨終結
And I always thought I'd end up here alone
緣何一切突然轉變
Somehow the world has changed
我回來了
And I've come home
帶回了，他們從你身上搶走的
To give you back the things they took from you
找到了你的感覺
And I feel you now
我不再孤單
I'm not alone
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看著我自己
When I see myself
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
我發現總有些事情
And I found something that was always there
它總會在你發現之前傷害你
Sometimes it's got to hurt before you feel
現在，我長大了，我不會再倒下
But now I'm strong. and I won 't kneel
感謝所有愛護我的人們
Except to thank who's watching over me
現在我感覺我如此強大
And somehow I feel so strong
我已不再是
And I've begun to be the one
從前的我
I never thought I'd be
我能真切的感覺到你
And I feel you now
我不再孤獨
I'm not alone
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看著我自己
And when I see myself
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
現在一切都如此的美麗
Now it's all so clear
我堅信
And I believe
我能克服一切困難
That everything's been opened up to me
我真切的感覺到你
And I feel you now
我不再孤獨
I'm not alone
我清楚的知道
I always know
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看著我自己
And when I see myself
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
我沐浴著陽光
And when I feel the sun
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看著我自己
And when I see myself
我總能感覺到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
謝謝觀賞